Subtitles by explosiveskull
Resync by Ahmed74
(CLOCK TICKING)
They're late.
(TRAIN HORN BLARING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(ENGINE REVVING)
Brenda,
we're coming up behind.
Keep 'em busy.
Hang on!
(LAUGHS)
Call it in!
Transport zero-one-niner,
we got trouble
on the rail line.
Mile 23, send backup!
Send backup!
PILOT: Roger that. On our way.
This is crazy, Thomas!
JORGE: Whoa!
Hang on.
THOMAS: Get me closer!
Come on, Vince!
(GRUNTS)
Vince!
Jump!
(GRUNTING)
Shit!
Let's go!
Hey! Berg!
PILOT: Zero-one-niner,
be advised.
You've taken on boarders
at the rear.
We're engaging the truck now.
Hey, Brenda, you got company!
Go, go, go!
Open fire.
JORGE: Watch out!
Holy shit!
Thomas, you're on your own.
Don't die.
Good luck!
We gotta move. Come on!
GUARD: Go, go! You heard him!
Give me the bag!
GUARD: Shoot!
Get down! Get down!
Vince?
We're set! Cover your ass!
GUARD: Go, go, go!
VINCE: Take cover!
GUARD: Come on!
Let's go! Let's go!
GUARD: We lost the rear five.
Stop the train!
(WHISTLES)
Newt!
All right, come on,
let's go. Come on!
Minho!
(ALL SHOUTING)
THOMAS: (MUFFLED)
Minho, can you hear me?
(YELLING)
This one. This one!
Oh, shit!
It's gonna be close.
Hello!
(WHOOPING)
Squirrelly bastard.
We got 'em! We got 'em!
PILOT: Step out of the vehicle
with your hands up.
GUARD: Let's go, boys.
Stop right there. Don't move.
I said freeze, asshole!
Whatever you say, hermano.
(GUARDS SHOUTING)
GUARD: Hold him back!
Y'all don't wanna do that now.
Hey, Fry.
Good to see you guys.
Go on, back up.
BRENDA: Uh-uh-uh!
Hi.
Newt, how you doing?
Don't rush me.
Shit!
Newt, get up here.
NEWT: Almost there.
Newt, go!
(BULLETS RICOCHETING)
- Where the hell are they?
- I don't know!
Go! There's too many of them!
All right, boys, we're here!
Keep moving!
- THOMAS: Come on!
- NEWT: Lower!
(GRUNTING)
GUARD: Cover me!
Go, go!
All right, we're clear!
Okay, we're going up.
Vince, get up here!
THOMAS: Now, Vince!
- Yeah!
- Whoo!
(LAUGHING AND WHOOPING)
We're going home, baby!
THOMAS: Yeah!
NEWT: All right, guys!
Good job. Whoo!
THOMAS: Yeah!
Aris.
Hey, you guys okay?
Yeah, we're fine.
Jesus.
There you are. Oh, God!
It's okay. You guys are safe.
All right? Just hang on.
HARRIET: I need
the bolt cutters.
Are you okay?
GIRL: I'm fine. How are you?
He's not here.
BOY: I'll take one.
WOMAN: Come on down.
You're safe here.
MAN: Need medical attention,
move to your left.
BOY: I need first aid.
WOMAN: Right this way, guys.
Come on down here.
VINCE: Come on in, guys!
MAN: Okay, guys, over here!
VINCE: All right, listen up.
I know you've all
been through hell.
I wish I could say
our troubles are over.
But we're not
through this yet.
WICKED's still out there.
They're not giving up.
'Cause you got
something they want.
They took you
because you're immune
to a plague that's wiping
out the human race.
And they think you're worth
sacrificing to find a cure.
Well, I don't.
So in two days,
when we get this tub
of rust seaworthy,
we're getting
the hell outta here.
We're gonna go to a place
where WICKED
will never find you.
A place you can start over.
A place you can call home.
- VINCE: Are you with me?
- (CROWD CHEERING)t
JORGE: (GRUNTS) Come on.
VINCE: (IN DISTANCE) Come on
up here. Let's get to work.
Come on,
I need some volunteers.
Let's go.
Let's get to work.
Let's get these crates
on the boat.
We got two days
before we leave.
All right.
Give me a hand up here.
May I help you?
It looks good.
How you feeling?
Awesome.
I was just asking.
I know, I know,
you're just asking.
Everybody's just asking.
Don't worry.
When I Crank out,
you'll be the first
to know, okay?
(GRUNTING IN PAIN)
HARRIET: Here, drink this.
Took you guys
long enough to rescue us.
It's good to see
you, too, bud.
So what happened?
I fought back.
Tried to, anyway.
You're lucky
you found us at all.
They had us
on the move a lot.
It felt like something
big was happening.
Any idea where
they were heading?
All I know is
they kept talking
about a city.
I didn't think
there were any cities left.
BRENDA: That's because
there aren't.
Not still standing, anyway.
Okay, wait. What about Minho?
Why wasn't he on the train?
I'm sorry, Thomas.
He was.
They got 40,
maybe 50 kids.
We're still compiling
an official count,
but the pilot
got a good look.
He thinks it was them.
Of course it was them.
What about the Berg?
We tracked it a few miles.
But someone must have
known about the locator.
They're totally off the grid.
GUARD: Move it, Immunes.
GUARD: C22.
B9.
We're searching the area,
but they're probably
long gone by now.
Oh, no, they're not
going anywhere.
He didn't get
what he really wanted.
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
THOMAS: There, that's it.
It's a few hundred miles.
Based on the railways,
everything that Aris
told us,
that's gotta be
where they're headed.
That's where
they're taking Minho.
We take everyone
who can fight.
Follow the roads
where we can.
We can make it back
within a week.
A week?
It took us six months
to get here.
We got over
100 kids here now.
We can't just hang out
here forever
after what we
just pulled.
You wanna wander off
to some random point
on the map.
You don't even know
what's there.
JORGE: I do.
It's been a few years,
but I've been there.
The Last City.
That's what WICKED called it.
It was their whole
base of operations.
If that city
is still standing,
that's the last place
you wanna go, hermano.
That's the lion's den.
It's nothing we haven't
done before.
VINCE: Yeah, with months
of planning,
and reliable information,
the element of surprise,
none of which we have now.
Vince, I've
thought this through.
Would you just
hear me out?
The last time we
went off half-cocked...
I lost everything.
You remember that?
Look, I know
it's Minho. All right?
But you can't ask me
to put those kids
on the line for one man.
I won't do it.
(STATIC ON RADIO)
GUARD: (ON RADIO)
Searching the grid now.
(WARBLED VOICES ON RADIO)
A is completed.
Scanning B-sector now.
Shit. Hit the lights.
Let's go, let's go!
(GENERATOR WINDING DOWN)
(BERG HOVERING IN DISTANCE)
VINCE: Jeez,
they're getting close.
You're right.
We can't stay here.
NEWT: Where do you think
you're going then?
(SIGHS) Newt...
Don't be a twat about it.
I'm already in.
Come on.
No. No, not this time.
Look,
even if we find Minho,
there's no guarantee
we make it back from this.
Well, you'll need all the help
you can get then, won't you?
(SCOFFS)
Well, we started this
together.
May as well
end it that way, too.
Okay.
Let's go get him back.
No.
(METALLIC CLANGING
IN DISTANCE)
Hey!
Hey! No, no, no.
Wait. Hey!
Hey, wait, wait!
Hey, it's okay! Hey!
(GATE OPENING)
(GRIEVER GRUNTING)
(GRIEVER HISSES)
(PANTING)
WOMAN: (MUFFLED)
How's he doing?
DOCTOR: (MUFFLED)
Breathing levels look strong.
Oh, shit!
(GRUNTS)
(YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
(METALLIC CLANGING)
(HISSING)
(ROARS)
(SHOUTING)
No! No!
(GROANING)
It's not as effective
as the maze,
but it seems to be working.
AVA: It's promising.
But we'll need a larger sample
to work with.
DOCTOR: All right.
Carry on.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
(MINHO PANTING)
(MINHO GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(YELLS)
MINHO: No! No!
(MINHO SCREAMING)
You want us to go in there?
I don't wanna come across
as too negative,
but if I was a Crank,
that's exactly
where I would be.
I don't think we have
much of a choice.
All right. I get shotgun.
FRYPAN: Well, here we go.
Yeah, just take it
nice and slow.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
(GAGGING)
It's okay. It's just one,
so take it slow,
go around him.
We'll be fine.
Take it slow.
- (GASPS)
- WOMAN: Please.
Please.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Help me.
- Please.
- (WINDOW THUDS)
- Please! Let me in.
- (JABBERING)
- Okay. Fry, we gotta go.
- Please! Open the door.
- You need to go right now!
- Why won't you open it?
- Just floor it, Fry!
- (CRANKS SCREECHING)
- Hold on!
- Floor it! Come on!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Come on, Fry, shake him!
- I'm trying!
Go.
Hang on!
Oh, God.
Frypan, watch out!
(ALL COUGHING)
THOMAS: Everyone okay?
FRYPAN: My hand.
(ENGINE STOPS)
My hand.
THOMAS: Fry, cover your eyes.
Oh, shit. You okay, man?
- NEWT: Yeah. You all right?
- FRYPAN: Shit, my hand.
Wait! Thomas!
Thomas, the door!
Can you get out?
Oh, shit. All right.
- FRYPAN: Newt, you all right?
- Fry, go around.
FRYPAN: I'm trying to get out.
Newt, you okay?
Yeah, I think so.
- Fry, you good?
- (CRANK SCREAMING)
Oh, shit.
Frypan, I think
we gotta move.
- Now!
- FRYPAN: Wait a minute!
- Right now!
- Fry, now!
Come on, what are you doing?
We gotta move! Come on!
- Come on!
- Hold on!
- Frypan gotta go! Come on!
- Wait!
Come on!
- Nice shot, Fry.
- Thanks.
(GROWLING AND SCREECHING)
THOMAS: Okay. We gotta go.
Go, go!
Fry, come on, let's go!
- Fry, let's move, let's go!
- NEWT: Go! Go! Go!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Watch out.
- Fry, you got any left?
- Yeah!
Okay. This way, this way!
Okay, Fry.
Other way, other way!
I'm out!
Shit!
Hey, get in!
- Go, Jorge, go!
- Go!
JORGE: Hang on!
I'm impressed!
You guys almost lasted
a whole day.
- You good?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry. I didn't wanna
bring you guys into this.
I think what
he's trying to say
is thanks for saving us.
You're welcome.
JORGE: Hey,
don't get your hopes up.
That checkpoint back there,
that was the city's
last defense.
If that was overrun,
chances are the city is, too.
Yeah, unless they figured out
some other way
to keep the Cranks out.
NEWT: Funny...
Spent three years
trapped behind walls,
trying to break out,
and now we wanna
break back in.
Yeah. It's hilarious.
Jorge, how do we get in?
Don't look at me, hermano.
Those walls are new.
I guess that's WICKED's
answer for everything.
Well, we ain't gonna
figure it out from up here.
Let's go!
NEWT: You really think
he's in there?
I guess we'll find out.
You know she's
gonna be there, too.
(ENGINE STARTS)
AVA: We just have to make sure
we have the resources.
And I'll keep in touch.
Excuse me.
Are you ready?
It'll be fine.
MAN: People are beginning
to lose faith, Doctor.
When you sealed off the walls,
you assured us
that it would only be
a temporary precaution.
Why have you now
denied all entry?
Because things are changing.
And not for the better.
Infection rates were up 300%.
Fortunately,
we may be on the verge
of a breakthrough.
This is Subject A7.
He spent over three years
in the Maze Trials.
The antibodies
produced in response
have been the strongest
we've ever seen.
We're extracting
a new serum as we speak.
And with your support,
we'd like to begin
human trials.
Thank you, Doctor.
That is very impressive.
But we have been
down this road before.
Frankly, we are all beginning
to wonder if...
If our resources couldn't be
better spent elsewhere.
- Meaning?
- WOMAN: Safe zones.
Protected areas
like the one we're in.
We could save
as many people as possible.
How many?
A thousand?
Two thousand?
And that's assuming
your protected areas
stay protected,
which we know they won't.
The infected already outnumber
the healthy three-to-one.
All you'd be doing
is delaying the inevitable.
Have any of you ever lost
someone to the virus?
A niece.
Anna.
I'm sorry we weren't
able to help her.
But imagine if we were able
to live with the virus.
To survive it.
Imagine being able
to tell Anna
that you could give her the
chance to live a normal life.
We've never been
this close to a cure.
And we've sacrificed a lot
to get this far.
Please,
don't let those sacrifices
be for nothing.
Nicely done.
They can be a tough crowd.
You handled them perfectly.
"Delaying the inevitable."
Thomas used to say
the same about us.
Do you still think about him?
I can help you with that,
those memories.
There's no reason
to keep holding on to them.
It's a simple procedure.
There is a reason.
I want to remember.
If we find a cure,
that's the only way all this
was worth it.
I hope you're right.
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
This place has really
gone through hell.
We just gotta stay together.
JASPER: (ON LOUDSPEAKER)
We are the voice
of the voiceless!
They hide
behind their walls,
thinking they can keep
the cure for themselves,
while they watch the rest
of us wither and rot!
But there are more of us
- than there are of them.
- (CROWD CHEERING)
And I say,
we rise up
and take back what is ours!
Let's bring back a victory!
(BEEPS)
Get Janson.
(CLAMORING)
Let us in!
That's it. That's our way in.
To the wall!
CROWD: Let us in!
Let us in! Let us in!
Thomas!
This is not
what you're looking for.
All these people
trying to find their way in,
you think you're gonna
find something they can't?
Came this far.
I'm not turning back now.
What the hell
did we get ourselves into?
JORGE: Get out of my way!
Get out of my way!
Thomas, this
doesn't feel right.
You were right, sir.
The drone sweep picked him up
outside the walls.
Get the guns online.
Hey, guys, we gotta go now.
Look.
(METALLIC CREAKING)
Let's go, let's go!
- Thomas, let's go.
- We gotta get out of here!
Let's go! Let's go!
Go! Go! Go! Come on!
Go! Keep going!
Come on!
FRYPAN: Move!
Come on! Get in! Get in!
JORGE: Let's go!
Let's go! Let's go!
Come on!
- NEWT: No way out!
- FRYPAN: Come on!
Newt! Newt!
NEWT: Get your hands
off of me!
No! Brenda!
Brenda! Brenda!
GUARD: Go, go, go!
THOMAS: Get off me!
Get off me!
Send out a patrol.
Tell them not to come back
until he's found.
GUARD: Let's go!
Get out!
JORGE: Where you going?
(GRUNTS)
Where is she,
you son of a bitch?
BRENDA: Hey! Hey! Hey!
Shit! Hey! Wait!
GUARD 1: Come on,
come on, come on.
BRENDA: I'm right here.
I'm right here!
- GUARD 2: Okay, okay, okay.
- All right. Okay.
I'm right here.
I'm right here!
Oh, Brenda.
GUARD 1: Everybody relax.
We're all on
the same side here.
What do you mean same side?
Who the hell are you?
Hey, Greenie.
Gally?
No way.
NEWT: No, wait!
Hold!
Stop! It's all right!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Stop! Stop it!
Stop.
(BREATHES SHAKILY)
- He killed Chuck.
- Yeah, I know.
I remember.
I was there too, all right?
But I also remember
that he was stung
and half out of his mind.
Just calm down. All right?
Come on.
Kind of had that coming.
Anybody else? Fry? Newt?
Do you know this guy?
He was an old friend.
NEWT: How?
(STAMMERS)
How is this possible?
We watched you die.
No, you left me to die.
And if we hadn't found you
when we did,
you'd be dead right now.
What the hell
are you doing here?
Minho.
WICKED has him here.
We're looking for a way in.
I can help with that.
Follow me.
I'm not going
anywhere with you.
Suit yourself.
But I can get you
through those walls.
After the maze,
I got picked up by a group
headed to the city.
They realized I was immune,
patched me up,
and they brought me here
to Lawrence.
This group's been at war
with WICKED
ever since they took control
of the city.
But WICKED can't hide behind
those walls forever.
Day's gonna come,
and they're gonna pay
for what they've done.
Listen, uh,
he doesn't get
a lot of visitors.
So, let me do the talking.
All right?
And try not to stare.
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
LAWRENCE: Rose took my nose,
I suppose.
Rose took my nose, I suppose.
Suppose, suppose,
took my nose...
I suppose.
Gally,
glad to see you made it back.
Jasper told me what happened.
GALLY:
It was a slaughter.
There's nothing we could do
against those guns.
No,
but they can only poke
the hornet's nest so long
before they get stung.
- (SNIFFS)
- (MUSIC STOPS)
Now, who are these people?
Why are they here?
We need to get into WICKED.
Gally said you can get us
through the walls.
Gally should know better
than to make promises
that he can't keep.
Besides, that wall
is only half your problem.
Getting inside WICKED
is impossible.
There might be a way now.
But it doesn't work
without Thomas.
LAWRENCE: Is that so?
Do you know what I am...
Thomas?
I am a businessman.
Which means that I don't
take unnecessary risks.
Why should I trust you?
'Cause I can help you.
You see, if you can get me
through those walls...
I can get you what you need.
What is it
that you think I need?
Time.
Every last drop.
(SCOFFS)
LAWRENCE: Is that what I need?
WICKED has something
we both want.
I'll tell you what.
Two can go for now.
The rest stay down here
with me.
Just a little insurance
to make sure
you find your way back.
We have a deal?
(CHUCKLES)
Gally, show him the way.
Be careful, Thomas.
Gally, take care of these two.
Yeah.
(NEWT GROANS)
NEWT: This is gross.
Jesus.
Yeah, this is great.
(GENERATOR POWERS UP)
GALLY: Stay with me.
We got a ways to go.
We're ready.
(MUFFLED SCREECHING)
TERESA: Shai?
Hi, Miss Teresa.
Hi.
Hey.
How are you feeling?
SHAI: Okay.
Is that gonna make me better?
I hope so.
Do you remember the story
you were telling me?
About the house
you grew up in?
I don't remember.
TERESA: The one by the lake?
(WINCING)
(PANTING)
It burns.
I know, I know.
There we go. All done.
You're so brave.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
JANSON: Oh,
that is incredible.
How soon can you administer
to the infected?
You show a lot of compassion
for someone who just
opened fire on a crowd.
You told me to do my job.
I had a shot. I took it.
And missed, apparently.
The patrols
never found a body.
Thomas is still out there.
What about her?
Does she know?
No.
She can't.
I need her to stay focused.
Elevate security levels
throughout the city.
I'm counting on you
to handle this, Janson.
(JINGLE PLAYS ON PA)
ANNOUNCER: (ON PA) Red zone,
departing the station
in five minutes.
Thank you.
This is a long way
from the Glade.
ANNOUNCER: (ON PA) Fifteen
minutes to mandatory curfew.
Please proceed home
in an orderly fashion.
Remember,
this is for your safety.
Thank you for your compliance.
Yeah, we better
get off these streets.
And I know it's hard, but act
like you've seen it before.
(SIREN BLARES)
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
They've definitely
upped security.
I'm guessing you shanks have
something to do with that.
All right,
let's get outta here.
All right, Newt, you're up.
I got it.
GALLY: There it is.
If WICKED's got Minho,
that's where
they'll be keeping him.
Lawrence has been trying
to find a way in for years.
Place is crawling
with soldiers.
They got
surveillance everywhere.
Scanners on every floor.
Sounds like a bloody fortress.
Yeah, I thought you said
you had a way in.
I might.
You might?
What the hell
do you mean "might"?
Take a look.
I said I had a way in.
I didn't say
you were gonna like it.
No. There's gotta be
another way.
Like what?
You've seen the building.
She is our only way in.
THOMAS: You really think
she's gonna help us?
GALLY: I don't plan on
asking for her permission.
Am I missing something here?
This is the same girl
who betrayed us, correct?
Same dick?
I like her.
What's going on?
What, are you afraid
your little girlfriend's
gonna get hurt?
Hmm?
Because this has
obviously never been
just about rescuing Minho.
Has it?
Wait, what are you
talking about?
Teresa.
She's the only reason
that Minho's even missing
in the first place.
Now we finally have an
opportunity to get him back.
And what? You don't want to
because of her?
Because deep down inside
you still care about her,
don't you?
Just admit it.
- Newt, I...
- Don't lie to me!
Don't lie to me!
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
Sorry about that. Back there.
I guess I can't
hide this anymore.
Why didn't you tell me?
Didn't think it would
make any difference.
All I know is that WICKED
must have put me
in that maze for a reason.
Maybe it was literally
just so they could tell
the difference
between immunes like you
and people like me.
You know we can
still fix this, Newt.
Okay? We can.
Don't worry about me.
This is about Minho.
Now he needs us.
So if there is even
the slightest chance
that we can save him,
we can get him out of there,
then we have to take that.
No matter what the cost.
Okay. I hear you.
GUARD: Let's get him up.
Minho.
Can you hear me?
There's a little girl here.
Her name is Shai Lun.
She's been infected
for three weeks now.
But, Minho,
you're going to save her.
And you can save
so many others.
Everything we're doing here,
it's working.
Do you understand?
That's why
this is so important.
(SIGHS)
I just wanted you to know.
(SOFTLY) Teresa.
Minho?
You're a traitor!
We trusted you!
- TERESA: Get off!
- GUARD: Hey, let her go!
Get off me! Get off me!
I'll kill you! You traitor!
You killed them all!
- (SCREAMING)
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(MINHO GROANING)
(PANTING)
Teresa, they need you
in the med lab.
It sounds serious.
(ALARM SOUNDING)
I'm sorry, Teresa.
(SCREAMING)
It's not your fault.
You did everything you could.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
ANNOUNCER: This is an alert.
Curfew is now in effect.
Anyone caught
in violation of curfew
will be subject
to immediate deportation.
Thomas?
(PANTING)
Thomas.
Hey, Teresa.
You shouldn't be here.
If Janson finds out
you're here...
I'm not staying.
It's just, uh...
I had to see you.
I have to ask you something.
Do you regret it?
What you did to us?
Sometimes.
But I did
what I thought was right.
I'd do it again.
Good.
JANSON: Taking
the edge off, I see.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Yes.
- It's a lovely city.
- Hmm.
The walls.
It's amazing what people
can accomplish
when their survival's
at stake.
Squeeze them hard enough,
there's nothing they can't do.
No line they won't cross.
You've had a bit of a setback.
It's nothing
we're not used to.
Not this time.
The virus is airborne.
It's inside the walls.
That serum
was our last chance.
Anyone not already infected
will be inside of a month.
Okay.
We can handle this.
We just need to evacuate
essential personnel,
set up at another safe zone
farther north.
We've still got 28 immunes
right inside this building.
We can find more.
You would.
You'd hunt every last
one of them down
till there was no one left.
In spite of everything
we've done to them,
everything we've put
them through.
At least we gave
them the tools
they'll need to survive.
Maybe they'll succeed
where we've failed.
Are you really telling me
that you're giving up?
After everything?
It's not about
giving up, Janson.
It's about knowing
when you've lost.
(PANTING)
Gally?
Here's how this is gonna go.
We're gonna ask you
some questions,
and you're gonna tell us
exactly what we need to know.
We'll start off simple.
Where's Minho?
You guys don't
seriously think...
Don't look at him.
Why are you looking at him?
Look at me.
He's not gonna help you.
Now, we know you have Minho
in the building.
Where?
He's with the others
in holding.
Sublevel three.
How many others?
28.
I can make that work.
TERESA: No.
No, you guys don't understand.
The whole level's restricted.
You can't get in
without a thumbprint ID.
That's why you're
gonna come with us.
Well, I don't know.
We don't necessarily need her.
Right?
Not all of her.
- We just need her finger.
- Gally, back off.
GALLY: What,
are you squeamish?
I guarantee you she's done
a lot worse to Minho.
That's not the plan.
Back off.
It won't make
a difference.
Do whatever you want to me.
You still won't get through
the front door.
The sensors will
pick you up the...
We know. We're tagged.
Property of WICKED.
You're gonna help us
with that, too.
Try to relax.
This is gonna sting.
Let's just get it over with.
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
She enjoyed that.
You're probably right.
Here. See if these fit.
- Thanks.
- FRYPAN: Thanks, Newt.
BRENDA: Better get going,
old man.
Long road ahead of you.
You sure I can't
talk you out of this?
It's your last chance.
You know, it's not like you
to shy away from a fight.
And it's not like you
to go looking for one.
I just can't help but think
if I walk out that door...
I'm never gonna see you again.
Since when do we go sticking
our necks out for strangers?
I was a stranger once, too.
(BOTH SIGH DEEPLY)
- Just don't leave us hanging.
- No.
Never.
She's looking good.
Healthy.
How've you been
getting her serum?
What are you talking about?
Brenda.
I didn't think
she'd still be alive.
When was her last treatment?
THOMAS: At the Right Arm.
The last time we saw you.
But that was months ago.
Thomas, that's not possible.
She should have turned by now.
There's no way she
could possibly still...
All right, that's enough.
You don't believe me?
Do you really
expect me to?
You made your choice.
Everything okay over here?
Yeah.
Yeah, we're done.
Nice try.
You were in love with her,
weren't you?
I don't know.
Just be careful.
You sort of have this problem
where you can't
walk away from people.
Even when you should.
You can't save everyone,
Thomas.
I can try.
THOMAS: Don't stop.
Go, go, go.
GALLY: Hold on. Hold on.
I can get in here.
THOMAS: Stay there.
Throw me the walkie.
(COUGHING)
(DRILL WHIRRING)
Frypan, we're in.
How you doing?
(GRUNTS)
Yeah, I'm getting there.
Tell Minho "Hi," for me.
THOMAS: Hang in there, buddy.
GALLY: This'll work.
Brenda, what's your status?
Status is, I'm working on it.
THOMAS: Copy. Just make sure
you're ready on your end.
Don't worry.
You know I'm gonna be there.
All right, let's go.
We got a signal.
Gally did it.
We're in.
Good.
Give me everything.
I want full control.
MAN: That's funny.
System's glitching.
I'll go check it out.
(GRUNTING)
MALE IMMUNE:
Get back, get back! Move!
(GUNSHOTS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(THUDDING)
(DOOR BUZZES)
Come on, let's go.
- Get them open.
- Let's go.
It's okay.
You guys are okay. Come on.
Come on, let's go.
Newt, check the other cell.
Come on, you guys are okay.
Come on.
The vault. How do I get in?
You can't.
Come on, guys. Come on.
GALLY: Guys,
this might take some time.
Shit.
He's not here.
Where is he?
This really couldn't wait
till morning?
You realize this could
kill him, right?
Taking this much,
all at once.
I have my orders.
Janson wants it all.
Somebody's moved him up
to the medical wing.
Thomas, that's on the other
side of the building.
Okay, take me to him.
Right now.
All right.
I'm coming with you.
Newt, no, you're not.
You have to stay here,
wait with Gally for the serum.
You can't do this on your own.
Minho comes first, remember?
Just go. We're wasting time.
I'll get the serum.
We'll meet you out back.
Okay, fine.
Let's go. Come on.
GALLY: Hey, Greenie.
Good luck.
THOMAS: Keep moving.
THOMAS: Come on, come on.
(ELEVATOR DOOR OPENS)
Hold it.
You're working late.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
See, that's what I like
about you, Teresa.
No matter how bleak
things get, you just...
Well, you never give up.
Times like this,
you need a friend
that you can count on.
I'll bear that in mind.
There is one thing
you should know.
One friend to another.
Thomas is here.
A surveillance picked him up
outside the walls.
Ava didn't want you to know,
but there is a chance that he
may try to contact you,
and if he does,
I'd like to think that
I'd be your first call.
Are you going to kill him?
Would that be a problem?
(ELEVATOR DOOR OPENS)
This is me.
Thomas, you have
to listen to me.
Getting that serum
won't save Newt.
It might buy him
some time, but...
NEWT: Just ignore her.
She's trying to get
inside your head.
Thomas, listen. You know
what's going on out there.
People are dying.
The world is dying.
There's something about
your blood I don't understand.
THOMAS: Open it.
If you let me run
some tests...
I promise I can protect you.
Yeah?
Like you protected Minho?
What are you doing?
How many people
is it gonna take?
How many more people
do they have to round up,
torture, kill?
Huh? When the hell
does it stop?
It stops when we find a cure.
There is no goddamn cure!
Don't waste your breath,
Teresa.
(GUN COCKS)
He made his choice long ago.
GUARD: Drop it, kid!
Back up.
Tell them to back off.
Tell them to back off!
Hey, Thomas, come on.
It's me.
I've known you longer
than you can remember.
You're not gonna shoot her.
You don't think so?
Okay.
Go on then.
Shoot her.
(THOMAS PANTING)
Prove me wrong.
Shoot her.
Clear! Clear!
GUARD: Move! Move!
(ALARM BLARING)
Your story better be good.
I just did you a favor.
Doors are sealed.
They can't get out.
Janson, I need them alive.
- Come on. Come on!
- GUARD: All right, let's move!
GUARD 2: Yes, sir!
Level three, now!
Okay. We need to get
outta here now.
You stay close to me.
Stick together.
You, you guard this with
your life. You understand?
All right.
Let's go.
Lock down the building.
Send everyone up to 20.
And someone shut off
those goddamn sirens!
GUARD: Yes, sir.
GUARD: Move! Move!
Stay low! Stay low!
Go! Go! Go!
Go! Stay low! Stay low!
Brenda, where are you?
We're here.
(TIRES SCREECH)
Come on, let's go.
All right. Let's go, let's go.
Quickly, quickly.
Front and back,
front and back. Let's go.
Wait, where's Thomas?
I was hoping he was with you.
Come on.
Wait! Wait!
Stay here with the kids.
Wait here...
I'll find him.
Just wait for us, okay?
We're not going anywhere.
Anything?
SOLDIER:
No sign of them yet, sir.
Yeah, well,
they're here somewhere.
They can't get out. Find them.
You two, that way.
The rest of you,
follow me. Let's go.
- GUARD 1: Yes, sir!
- GUARD 2: Affirmative.
ANNOUNCER:
Code 22 in progress.
All R-16 personnel, report
to their assigned stations.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Get down. Get down.
GUARD: Move! Move! Move!
BRENDA: Stay quiet.
GUARD: Got someone here.
Sorry, Thomas.
(ENGINE STARTS)
GUARD: Hey,
someone's got the bus.
Hold on!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
- GUARD 1: Watch it!
- GUARD 2: Stop!
GUARD 3: No, no, no!
It's all right!
GUARD: Load up! Load up!
Let's go! Move it!
Move! Move!
ANNOUNCER: All R-16 personnel,
report to their
assigned stations.
Thomas! No!
(GUNSHOTS)
Minho? Minho!
- Oh, shit!
- Freeze!
Minho!
THOMAS: (MUFFLED)
Minho, where are you?
Minho!
NURSE: Doctor,
he's coming out of it.
Get me another sedative.
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
Shit!
GUARD: Over here!
There they are!
I'll cut him off!
Newt, get down! t
Shit! I'm almost out.
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Get back.
Nice. All right.
Let's go! Go!
GUARD 1: You two, freeze!
Get down on the ground. Now!
I said get your...
- (YELLING)
- (GUARD 1 SCREAMS)
(YELLING)
(PANTING)
Minho.
(ALL GRUNT)
Is this real?
GUARD 2: I got him!
I got him! Over here.
Go! This way!
Come on!
GUARD 3: You three! Stop!
Come on.
In here, in here.
(GRUNTS)
Newt, come on.
Somebody get this door open.
Yes, sir!
Oh, shit.
(DRILL WHIRRING)
Any ideas?
Maybe.
(GRUNTING)
Okay, it's doable.
Just need
a little running start.
GUARD 4: Almost through.
You sure about this?
Not really.
Nice pep talk.
Yeah, we're all
bloody inspired.
- GUARD 5: Move it! Move it!
- Shit.
Go! Go!
MINHO: Thomas!
THOMAS: Oh, shit!
- Minho, you okay?
- Yeah.
(ALL PANTING)
(GUNS COCKING)
SOLDIER:
You three, don't move.
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
SOLDIER: Take it easy.
Uh-uh-uh!
Don't even think about it.
Get on your knees
with your hands in the air.
You son of a bitch.
(SCREAMING)
Gally?
Minho.
You guys are nuts.
I'll explain later.
(PANTING)
ANNOUNCER:
Attention all personnel.
Drop the net.
Declare martial law. No one
leaves until they're found.
It's done, sir. We already
have eyes on the bus.
Our patrols are in pursuit.
What bus?
(SIRENS WAILING)
Shit! Hold on!
(YELLS)
(LAUGHING)
Shit!
Get out of the vehicle.
Don't move.
You're doing great.
SOLDIER: Now step away
from the vehicle.
I said step away
from the vehicle!
Put your hands in the air.
(SIREN BLARING)
Drop the weapon!
Here we go.
Push in! Push in! Go! Go!
- That bus does not leave!
- GUARD: Move! Move in!
Come on, hold on to something!
Here we go.
Circle up! Go! Go!
Hold fire!
(IMMUNES SCREAMING)
Brace yourself.
(THUDDING)
Sorry.
Shit.
(METALLIC CREAKING
AND CLANGING)
Hold on to something!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(THUDS)
(METALLIC CREAKING)
(ALL SCREAMING)t
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
Okay. Everybody off.
(MAN GRUNTING)
JANSON: Shut up.
They're not out yet.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(ALL PANTING)
Well, they're
definitely pissed.
How far are the tunnels?
Uh, maybe 12 blocks from here.
(NEWT COUGHING)
We can make it.
Newt, how are you feeling?
(GROANS)
Terrible.
It's good to see you though.
(PANTING)
Hey.
How long has he been
like this?
He'll be okay.
We just gotta get to Brenda.
She's got the serum.
Come on, let's go.
Hey, Newt.
Come on, bud.
We gotta get you up. Let's go.
- (NEWT GRUNTS)
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- You okay?
- NEWT: Yeah.
Why you helping us, Gally?
I put a spear
through your chest.
Yeah.
Nobody's perfect, man.
(GASPS SOFTLY)
BRENDA: Lawrence!
Wait, guys.
Wait, wait, wait.
Where is everyone?
Wait here, guys. Wait.
Thomas!
BRENDA: Hey!
FRYPAN: Lawrence!
BRENDA: Everything's gone.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(ALL GASP)
Don't be scared.
I may not be pretty,
but we all know who
the enemies are,
cowering behind those walls!
(ALL CHEERING)
They have a name
for people like us in there.
They call us Cranks!
But I say that
they are the monsters.
(ALL CHEERING)
They're the ones
who started this war,
but tonight,
we will finish it.
Follow me.
Follow me,
and we will show them
the faces of the people
that they have chosen
to forget!
(ALL CHEERING)
Follow me
and this city is yours!
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
(CROWD CHANTING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
Let's move it!
Let's go!
GUARD: Control,
you seeing this?
Please advise.
Holy shit.
Get turrets one
and two ready to fire.
Guns aren't responding.
I'm locked out.
All right. Move forward.
Open fire! Open fire!
- (EXPLOSIONS)
- (ALL SCREAMING)
We're supposed
to take down WICKED,
not the whole damn city.
Gally, come on.
(SIRENS BLARING)
ANNOUNCER: This is
a mandatory evacuation.
The last transport leaves
in 38 minutes.
Please proceed to the roof.
I repeat, this is
a mandatory evacuation.
Teresa, what are you still
doing here? We have to leave.
No, I can't leave.
Not without Thomas.
It's too late for that.
He's gone.
No. You don't understand.
I need more.
Come. Look.
It's not just slowing
the virus down.
It's destroying it.
We need to find Thomas.
Tunnels are right up ahead.
Shit!
Hey! Stay low! Stay low!
(SIREN WAILING)
(COUGHS)
Shit!
Get ready!
All right, move up! Move up!
Frontline down!
Damn it!
What are they waiting for?
(EXPLOSIONS)
(CROWD YELLING)
GALLY: Get down, get down!
Stay down! Stay down!
We gotta go. We gotta go.
Come on.
Let's move, let's move.
THOMAS: (ON WALKIE-TALKIE)
Get him in, get him in.
Brenda, are you there?
Thomas, I'm here.
(EXPLOSION)
Shit! You okay?
We're not gonna make it.
Wait, what are you
talking about?
- Don't let them get away!
- (GUNFIRE)
Just take the others.
Get everybody out
while you still can.
No.
Brenda.
I'm not leaving you.
Okay?
So forget it.
Even though you should?
(DISTANT GUNFIRE)
(ENGINE HUMMING)
BRENDA: Thomas, don't worry.
I'm coming to you.
What are you talking about?
Our ride's here!
(LAUGHS)
Just look for us
near the tunnels.
FRYPAN: Let's go, guys! Move!
Our ride's here!
- BRENDA: Careful.
- FRYPAN: Move! Move!
BRENDA: Watch your step. Okay?
Vince?
Hey, it's good
to see you, too.
JORGE: Yeah, I know.
I picked up a stray.
Let's get out of here,
all right?
BRENDA: We're not done yet.
Thomas is still inside.
Well, let's go get him then.
- Hell yeah.
- All right, let's go.
- On board. Everybody.
- Let's go! Step up! Step up!
- We gotta move, we gotta move.
- Take a seat, harness...
(EXPLOSIONS)
All right.
Newt, we're almost there.
NEWT: Just leave me.
Back! Back!
Let's go! Let's go!
Take 'em out!
(ENGINE HUMMING)
- Okay, that's them.
- Yeah.
It's them. We gotta go.
- We gotta go.
- Go without me, man.
You should just...
(COUGHING)
(WHEEZING)
Minho.
You gotta run ahead,
grab the serum,
and get back to us
as soon as you can.
Minho, go.
He's right. I can cover.
(PANTING)
Thank you.
Thank you, Minho.
Hey, you just hang on.
You hear me?
GALLY: Go, Minho, go!
Okay, they're through.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BREATHING RAPIDLY)
THOMAS: (MUFFLED) Newt? Newt?
Hey! Hey! Newt! Hey!
We're gonna try this. Okay?
We gotta move, now.
Let's get you up, come on.
- Let's go, come on.
- No. No, Thomas.
No, Newt. Later. Later.
Really gotta go.
- Come on.
- Look, you gotta take this.
- We gotta get you up, now.
- No, just take it!
(BREATHING HARSHLY)
Please.
Please, Tommy. Please.
All right.
All right. I need you
to give me everything you got.
You and me, right now.
Let's go. You ready?
Come on, ready? Here we go.
- One, two, three.
- (GRUNTING)
Get back, guys, get back!
Oh, man.
It's okay, guys. We're getting
out of here soon.
We can't stay here, Bren.
Don't worry. They'll be here.
THOMAS: Come on. Come on.
(GRUNTING)
We're almost there, Newt.
Stay with me, come on.
(GAGGING)
Newt, no, no. Hey!
(BREATHING RAPIDLY)
Come on.
(GRUNTING)
TERESA: (ON PA) Thomas?
(ECHOING) Can you hear me?
I need you to listen to me.
I know you have
no reason to trust me,
but I need you to come back.
Thomas, you can save Newt.
There's still time for him.
There's a reason
Brenda isn't sick anymore.
It's your blood.
Do you understand?
She isn't sick,
because you cured her.
She doesn't have to be
the only one.
All you have to do
is come back.
And this will all
finally be over.
Please.
Just come back to me.
I know you'll do the right...
Newt?
(GROWLING)
Newt? Newt, it's me. It's me!
Brenda!
Where's the serum?
(NEWT SCREECHING)
(PANTING)
Tommy, kill me!
Newt, I'm here.
Newt, please!
Please!
(PANTING)
I'm sorry, Tommy.
It's okay. It's okay.
No!
(GROWLS)
Brenda!
Thomas!
Stay down, stay down!
(GRUNTS)
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMS)
Newt.
(KNIFE STABS)
(GRUNTS)
Tommy.
No, no.
No, no, no.
Newt?
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
(GUN COCKS)
Is it true?
Newt.
Could I have saved him?
You can save us all.
(SNIFFLES)
(SOBBING SOFTLY)
AVA: (SOFTLY) It's okay.
Just leave the others alone.
I promise.
- I will...
- (GUNSHOT)
(GRUNTS)
(THUD)
(STRENUOUS BREATHING)
Oh, Thomas.
You should have run.
TERESA: Thomas.
Can you hear me?
(EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE)
JANSON: Do you know what
this place is, Thomas?
It's a lifeboat.
And the whole world
might be sinking,
but doesn't mean that
we have to go down with it.
How much longer?
TERESA: It's almost done.
Why don't you just kill me?
Kill you?
No, we don't wanna do that.
We're gonna take
special care of you.
We'll keep you alive.
- Just.
- (GRUNTS)
And in return,
you will give life
to the rest of us.
The ones we choose
to save, anyway.
Of course, there's not gonna
be enough for everyone.
Hard choices are gonna
have to be made.
In time, the Flare virus
will burn itself out.
The only question is,
who will be the ones
left standing?
And thanks to you,
to this,
we finally get to choose.
A future of our own making.
To your health.
(BOTH GASPING)
Okay, let's get out of here.
(GRUNTS)
Come on.
(SCREAMS)
THOMAS: No!
Get back here.
Get back!
No!
Give it to me.
Give it to me!
THOMAS: Teresa!
(GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
Come on.
(GRUNTING)
Okay.
That's enough.
(GROANING)
Weapons ready!
On my command.
Charge it!
Ready.
Fire!
Teresa!
We need to get out of here.
What's wrong?
(PANTING)
Thomas?
Thomas!
(GRUNTING)
- Okay. Okay, we need to...
- Oh, shit...
Find something.
Here. Here!
Just put pressure on it.
Hold it.
(LABORED BREATHING)
You gotta go.
No.
Not without you.
(STEAM HISSING)
(MUFFLED GROWLING)
I admit, Teresa,
you had me fooled.
I thought we were friends.
(CLANGING)
Maybe it's just
in your nature to betray
the people closest to you.
(CLANGING)
Come on.
Let's not prolong this.
We both know
there's no way outta here.
Let's not make this
any more painful
than it needs to be.
Thomas.
Teresa.
(TERESA GASPS)
No. No.
I think you have
something of mine.
Not that.
Where is he?
Just take it.
Leave him alone.
What is it with you two?
You think he's so special?
He's a lab rat.
He was born with a gift.
He never had to fight for it,
he never earned it.
He doesn't deserve it.
Maybe.
But it's his.
What about you, Thomas?
What do you have to say?
Don't you have enough blood
on your hands already?
You might not have been
able to shoot her.
But I can.
Okay. Fine.
Have it your way.
(GUN COCKS)
THOMAS: Janson.
(GRUNTS)
Missed, you little shit.
Did I?
(GLASS CRACKING)
Oh, shit.
(GROWLING)
Come on. We need to go.
(SCREAMING)
This way. Here.
Come on.
(COUGHING)
(TERESA GASPS)
(THOMAS BREATHING RAPIDLY)
(CRYING)
I'm sorry.
I tried.
I know.
I think I got him.
Yeah, that's him.
I'll get the hatch.
All right, I got him,
I got him.
Let's go, let's go.
Come on.
No!
I can't get any closer.
MINHO: Thomas!
TERESA: Now!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Come on, come on, come on.
- MINHO: Come on!
- FRYPAN: Come on, Thomas!
Give me your hand!
Get closer!
Jump!
Lower!
No!
You gotta get closer.
(EXPLOSION)
Come on!
VINCE: Yeah!
- Come on, reach! Come on!
- Reach!
- Pull him up!
- Pull!
Come on!
VINCE: Come on!
Teresa!
No!
(INAUDIBLE)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(SEAGULLS SQUAWKING)
(WAVES CRASHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
VINCE: We have come
a long way together.
So many have sacrificed
so much
to make this place possible.
Your friends
and your family.
So here's to the ones
who couldn't be here.
Here's to the friends we lost.
This place is for you.
It's for all of us.
But this,
this is for them.
So, in your own time,
in your own way,
come make your peace.
And welcome to the Safe Haven.
- Yeah!
(ALL CHEERING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
You all want some food?
This is gonna be
a good home for us.
Yeah.
You had this on you
while you were passed out.
Figured I'd keep it
safe for ya.
Thanks, Minho.
See you out there.
See ya.
NEWT: Dear Thomas...
This is the first letter
I can remember writing.
Obviously, I don't know if I
wrote any before the maze.
But even if it's not my first,
it's likely to be my last.
I want you to know
that I'm not scared.
Well, not of dying, anyway.
It's more forgetting.
It's losing myself
to this virus.
That's what scares me.
So every night I've been
saying their names out loud.
Alby...
Winston, Chuck.
And I just repeat them
over and over,
like a prayer,
and it all comes
flooding back.
Just the little things,
like the way
the sun used to
hit the Glade
at that perfect moment
right before
it slipped beneath the walls.
And I remember the taste
of Frypan's stew.
I never thought
I'd miss that stuff so much.
And I remember you.
I remember the first time you
came up in the Box.
Just a scared little Greenie
who couldn't even remember
his own name.
But from that moment
you ran into the maze,
I knew I would
follow you anywhere.
And I have.
We all have.
If I could do it
all over again, I would
and I wouldn't
change a thing.
And my hope for you
is that when you're looking
back years from now,
you'll be able
to say the same.
The future's
in your hands now, Tommy.
And I know you'll find a way
to do what's right.
You always have.
Take care of everyone for me.
And take care of yourself.
You deserve to be happy.
Thank you for being my friend.
Goodbye, mate.
Newt.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
Resync by Ahmed74