Cisco, what happened?
(Frost), (Frost) ...
(Bar)
Help her, help her
(Iris) Iris
Help her
Will you be okay?
When I pulled Iris out of the mirrorworld and I resisted you
This created a molecular anomaly, and it separated all its neurotransmitters
Her brain seems to have been rewired - how do we get it back?
I don’t know, all we can do now is let her rest while I do more tests
Will you be okay?
I remember everything how I hurt my team
And how she pushed Iris toward the gate, leaving Camila and Singh stranded
- I'm sorry - that wasn't you
- Yeah, I was. - No, it wasn't
You are not right, believe me, we understand that
So, we'll forget it and go ahead, okay?
We're a team, we're protecting each other - we'll find a way to save Iris.
And Camila and Singh too, I promise
Eva is still free and I can't stop her because I lost my speed
But you'll deter it, I'll do a thorough examination of the artificial velocity field
It worked in the past, and it will work again
All we have to do is define ... - No
I am satisfied with this thing, you have seen what was made of me
I'm not (Thon), the connection to the synthetic isn't going to work for me
And since the real velocity field is over
- "Central City Police" - this could be delayed
- Did your wife try to attack you? Why did your neighbor force you to look in the mirror?
Hey, Central City Police here. - If not your uncle, who is he?
You want to help bring your daughter here, Mrs. Derbond ...
- To get arrested - she's in trouble
We want to help her see things more clearly
People change sometimes, overnight
Captain, can I talk to you?
- It matters - sorry
Miserable, Sue, I thought you were going to disappear with Ralph so we could clear both of you
Yeah, Ralph tracks down the evidence. Arrest me, if I wanted to, I should have come
Can you tell me what's going on to push you to risk your freedom?
The two people on the inside are not my parents
I know, that sounds hard to believe when (Ralph) mentioned aliens
I thought he was too crazy, but I assure you, they are not my parents
Yes, I believe you
We received more than 100 calls in the past hour with the same complaint
Everyone said that people who had known them for years were no longer normal
Do you think this has something to do with the mess at McCulloch?
Miserable, I know what's going on
step away
What was this?
Chaos raged in downtown Central ...
Even so, she's still my grandmother (Rank), you know?
Because I was at Geters buying coffee
Suddenly, two hands appeared from the table and tried to catch me
Luckily, Chester P.Rank is always vigilant
Hey, call me (Joe) No matter what happens outside, it's spreading
- Yeah, Eva's strength is increasing. Right
I analyzed the footage from Eva's live interview
It's not just messing with mirrors but any reflective surface now
I think it makes sense, photons are fundamental particles found in all of nature
So, as long as there is light from either a natural or an artificial source ...
Call Joe back, we need to turn off the lights in town
We can urge the mayor to declare a state of emergency. - Well, I'll take care of it
Why did Eva do this? Why do you want to send us to the mirrorworld?
You want to get rid of us. These are not just kidnappings
It is a complete sweep
And with every person you replace, Eva's army grows.
Whoops, kidnappers ... What are we going to do now?
Director, you must recover
We can't work in The Citizen without you
So, please come back to us, okay?
We won't abandon you, especially Barry.
What the two of you is amazing
No matter how strong you are separately, you are stronger together
Don't let Eva McCulloch ruin the two of you
The mayor is doing everything she can to cut off the electricity
(Joe) said it would not be comprehensive but I said we will accept what is possible
Regardless, I'll close all the windows at Star Labs.
We have to cover all the mirrors too and turn off the lights
- Yes, I will take care of it - I hope the townspeople will follow our example
If I had the speed, I would have gone on a ride and helped people stay safe
There has to be a way to save them all
- And recover (Iris) - "There is a way, there is a way ..."
"There is a way, there is a way"
Did you say anything?
Hey buddy, where's Barry?
(Bari) ...
You are powerless, Flash.
"But I can help you"
- Would you like to help me? - Would you like to help?
- Tell me how I saved my wife - she has to get back where she belongs
You all are
Return to the world of the mirror
You see, in the past 6 years I've seen people like joseph.
And they destroy the blessings around you
A glorious world full of wonders
You and everyone else on this planet have failed ...
And now, I will fill it with my sons
It will be treated by everyone with respect
What will happen to us? You will adapt to your new world
As I did
Don't worry, Barry, I'm not going to kill anyone, I'm not your enemy
But I am like a mother to this new and better world
You want me to surrender? Just like Ramsay did ...
Ramsay thought he was a hero
But it was not like that
As for you, yes
Lead your people to the mirrorworld, they will follow you and be happy
- Were you happy? - Stop resisting me!
You were watching me, Eva.
You know I'm going to risk my life to save this city
This is brave words, Flash.
But are you really ready to do whatever it takes to ensure humanity's survival?
My inverter technology applications are endless
I can grow crops ten times as abundantly as I can end famine in one day
Why didn't you?
Why didn't you do the really important work?
Why not make the world a better place?
Because you are helpless
I am able, and I will
I am not a human being ... but what is better
For this, I show you mercy
So, please
Think about my accident and make the right decision
The satellites have located McCulloch. Barry, I won't lose you either
Frost is ready to emerge
- That's cool - How did you escape?
- I didn't run away, Eva left me alone - Why? What did she want?
- She wanted to tell us we couldn't win - I hope you answered her firmly
No, she's right ... we can't win
- (Nash) - No, my name is Harrison.
Dr. (Harrison Wells)
Listen, I don't know who you are but I watched Nash die
- And all the other Wells characters died with him - to be exact
And when Nash Wells gave his life to provide power for the artificial speed field
Transport all particles from the multiverse of all Wells characters
To the fusion ball except for 1.0 percent, which is me
How did the molecules become a person?
Lee theory, when Nash and all Wells characters.
They stepped out of the chronology asking the universe ...
Act of balance
(Wells) has one to compensate for all those losses
Isn't that cool?
Crisis, an event happened ... Bring people from other planets here
To the same planet in the same timeline
Time coalescence? That could explain what happened
Of all of Wales's characters
You the one who wanted to meet him the most
- I ... - (Barry Allen)
I know
Wells' characters may have passed, but they left an imprint
Memories ... so let me say whatever was wrong ...
Let me help you with this because she wanted me to
You cannot, this enemy that we face is very strong
- I also lost my speed - you are the epitome of love
Listen, anyone can save the world with speed and power
But this requires a true hero, an unparalleled hero
To save him with love
What is the meaning of this? - That means, run, Barry.
Run to love
- Nash? Both
Allegra, Nash was ...
He loves you so much
(Wales) New
How is this possible? Hey, you are here to save us, right?
- Besides, which character is this? - I'm the first character
Well, I asked Allegra to post a story in The Citizen to warn residents about Eva.
- Well done - thank you
What is the matter? - This window was covered
where is everybody?
I have a strong feeling of passion, confidence and focus
Joe, I ...
You have to surrender, Captain
Atmosphere)? Here is Captain West, I ask for support
- No one will come, Captain - (Cecil), run
Windows ...
- My phone is not working - it must have disabled transmission
Unfortunately, (Wales), (Wales) ... and this (Wales) too
And Wells too, that's how you got here. Any questions?
- I don't understand how ... - Right
Help, guys we need help
(Su), (Ralph)?
Where's your face, man? Looks like mashed potatoes
No, his 260 degree body temperature does not touch him
You mean someone caused the rubber man to melt?
- What a fool - text me (Ralph)
He asked me to meet him at McCulloch Labs.
- He was looking for evidence to acquit you, right? Yes
He thought that there would be no security because of the power outage
He was inside when (Eva) blew up the whole place and I was shot
He came out carrying this
Can you cure it? Well, I'll move it to the biological isolation unit
Okay, we'll go over here from here, Ralph.
Come with me, Sue, let me check your arm
This sounds strange
- Is there anything? I mean, not quite ...
Hey, yeah, ralph found evidence to exculpate Sue.
The hero remains a hero - to be sure
I know you still exist
I will never stop fighting to get to you
Maybe this is the epitome of love but it's only because you are in my heart
Please ... come back to me
I don't understand, exactly how will you be able to regain your speed?
Iris is the key
- Yeah, I still don't understand - the velocity field, we thought it collapsed, right?
I felt the spark with Iris a while ago
Barry, you lost your speed
No, the velocity field is a fundamental part of the universe, so in theory ...
In theory, he might never have collapsed - and you think he's still in Iris.
I always wondered why I was chosen to be the epitome of love
And what does that have to do with my speed? I think this is because of my relationship with Iris.
Our love is as strong as the thunderbolt that struck me 7 years ago
And Iris has been enjoying speed in the past
And (Nora) was speeding, and her spark was purple and yellow
Yeah, how romantic
If the velocity field energy is still in Iris, how do we extract it from it?
Well, we have to restart the artificial velocity field
To derive strength from an organic source rather than an artificial one
I can help with this
- Well, I need ... - I'll take care of it
If it works, we can play Eva together
Let the new life begin, my children
Go, just go
Open the door
It's too late, Captain, this is my mother's world now.
- Can she come in? Yes
This door is not designed to withstand a tactical force
- It should have been - with these old buildings, there are main pipes
Humans have taken this world for granted, Captain.
We won't
I won't leave you, please come Joe.
Kiss me (Jenna) on my behalf
Now, go
Okay, I'm done, how long is it yet to reconnect the power supply?
- Power cycles have been redirected - and the fusion ball setup re-set
I must say, is this how you guys do?
Because all this friction with so much raw energy
This is a big risk
Allen, if you're wrong about Iris, every atom in your body will split in half.
‫"(باري)"
We need you
- We need you - I'll be fine
Energy is increasing
"Run, Barry, run."
"Run to love"
Yeah, that's the true velocity field
- Amazing - normal speed is complete
We need you
I need you
I knew you would find a way back to me
You will always be my strength
Do not be afraid you will go to a better place, I promise
Take them
Both
No, Flash, you've made up your mind
Now, face the consequences
It's over, Eva.
Why doesn't Flash use its speed?
Its body is made of quantum protons that are capable of a lower speed than light
- So, technically ... - it's faster than him
- Not Cecil. - No
But it is close to here
If you want to be with her ...
There is one way
Why do I trust you?
You don't have any choice
We could have worked together to achieve the common good
It is too late now the era of the human race is over
My children will occupy the world and I am their mother and daughter
Tonight my reign as Queen of the Mirror World begins
In fact, this is only the beginning
Did you like the sound waves, madam?
But hey, there's more
Now, Flash!
That's not fair, you brought your team
Maybe I should get my team
It looks like a Saturday night in Iron Heights.
Protect me!
- I can't fix these guns in time - you have to think about something else
- Quickly ... - Let's do this
(Frost)!
Each villain has a weakness, what did we miss
Barry needs more than speed to win this fight
Spend it
Flash, no, Eva, please don't
It's too late for Flash's chance
you too
- (Eva), you are destroying this world - No, I am freeing it from being overrun
My children deserve this world more than human beings
I'll deal with it, join the others
- (Eva) - You're not giving up, right?
Ok, bye
This is impossible
I'm still not strong enough to overpower me
- Not yet ... - (Eva)
You told my husband that you wanted to bring peace to this world
You are using excessive force against defenseless people
Eva, my surrogate ...
She was connected to this world and herself
But your other children ... are full of hatred
Look around you
Is this your concept of peace?
no no
Is this what you really want?
- Back off, this is our chance ... - No, please, just wait
Both
No, I ...
I wanted to improve things
You have failed two worlds
Eva, it's never too late to do the right thing
You told me about your dream of helping people, you still can
Here and now, by finishing this
The foundation of a better world is empathy, not violence
The true Queen knows this
We'll go, we're going
It doesn't work
They became too powerful to control them
We have succeeded
What about the people we lost?
Commander Singh? Sir, what happened?
- Are we ... - dead?
No, policewoman, we are alive
I'm sure we owe our lives to some accelerator, and his wife, too
(Of)
- Is that you, right? No, I'm Shwapaka.
It's Camila, the real one if she comes back ...
This means that the rest of the people of Central have returned as well
where are you? I'm at the Citizen headquarters.
I was in that other place I never thought I would ever leave
Do not leave, I will kiss you as if it is our last day
I love you, camila.
Me too
Do you want someone to drive you? Ice Bridge, the most secure transportation way
Honestly, I find this hard to believe
So what are you going to do now?
I will return to the world of the mirror
To do what I had to do a long time ago
Starting over
This time, my children will be born out of love, not hate
They will be free to choose their own path
Good luck
Is there any reference to Eva? Both
It seemed the Mirror Realm Queen was really serious about starting over
Iris, what you did there ...
What if you were now a superhuman?
I'm sure Eva stripped me of my power in the mirrorworld when I left
Perhaps when she returned to the mirrorworld, she closed the gate ...
Without it, you have no powers
Well, the substitutes disappeared and we all got back
(Singh) Derbond and Camila.
It was a good day at work folks
Okay, where's O (OG Wells)? He's with Cisco and Allegra.
They wanted to bid him farewell individually
Are you sure you should leave?
I heard Team Flash always includes a Wells character.
This is overrated, but Flash has regained its speed
The Mirror Realm Queen is back where she belongs
It's time - but I need someone to train me
You have to follow your own path and show that I have my own path
The universe brought me back to life
Somehow, and now, I can see the 92 years of that life
Past, present and future simultaneously
And somehow, I can travel to whatever moment I want
Perpetual Wells, that's new
This is amazing and of no use if I can't share it with my beloved wife, Tess.
We have had 4 great years
Together, before ...
Before we were killed
Now, I have a choice between moving forward from this moment on without it
And back to it
I want to reclaim those 4 years that we spent together
Over and over again, endlessly, until my hour comes
Good luck
Allegra, good luck to you
I get you, you want to be with the person you love
Camila and I would be lucky if we got half of what I experienced with Tess.
You will
- It's weird, isn't it? - Yes, we just met
- As if I hardly even know you - we hardly know each other
- I mean, you don't look like him at all. - Who?
The Harrison Wells you knew - or who you thought was Harrison Wells
- Of course, it turned out to be an idiot. - An idiot?
Yes Yes
How do you miss someone you barely know?
Before you leave, how do you travel through time exactly?
It's easy, just that
that easy
Well, we talked to Captain West. Actually, I did.
Ralph's voice scared him - What don't you like about my voice?
- Your voice sounds great - Yeah, the helmet reminds me of Daft Punk.
What? You know I love dancing so much
Don't do this, don't do, don't do ...
Ralph, don't worry, after a few days in the biological isolation unit, you'll be back the way you were
Anyway, nice to see you again, Caitlyn, and Frost too
After I confirmed my parents' safety and after the police obtained evidence to acquit me
- It's thanks to Ralph ... - We have to celebrate
Sue, have you ever thought about joining Team Flash?
We can hire someone with your skills
Me, in the same team with the perfect man who is not good at dancing?
This is not what I like
Plus, Ralph and I have work left to do
Blackhall is over, but there is an organization like it in every country in the world
Take advantage of good people like my parents
- We'll visit it - get rid of it
Ralph, we've been through a lot since you joined this team
Get off this, Barry, don't say goodbye, I'll be back when you least expect it
Frost, we're going on that trip, okay?
- She says, of course - if you need help, just let us know
- I'll hurry up to you two. - Thanks
Do the same
- Come on dude - stay cool, (Debney) departing
They make a great team
and we too
"18 hours ago"
Translation: Image Production House