What have you done?!
- Still at it?
- I think I figured out how
to track the thing that attacked us.
So... what are we looking at?
A spectrograph from
the scene of the attack.
That is a rare geothermic
isotope that I reprogrammed
our satellites to scan for.
If we get a hit...
Then we can track our target.
- Nice work.
- Thanks.
Barry, you've been at this all night.
Maybe you should take a
break and get some rest.
I'm not gonna rest while
that thing is still out there.
Besides, with Ralph
overseas for a while,
and Frost still recovering...
Oh, I'd say she's more
than just recovering.
Check out this frosty twist.
Are my back meds still wearing off?
I'm seeing double.
Yeah, you and me both.
I know this is a lot to take in.
Told you they'd freak.
www.TUSUBTITULO.com
-DIFUNDE LA CULTURA-
Cecile.
Who are you?
What do you want?
It's time to come home now, Cecile.
- Get away from me.
- You cannot control me.
You never did learn your lesson.
Babe!
Cecile, Cecile. What's wrong?
You were screaming.
No, no, no. I saw... I saw someone.
I saw someone, they were
right there and then they...
There's no one here. No one else here.
Except us.
You've been working
too hard on those cases,
must have fallen asleep.
It felt so...
But the...
The danger, it was... it was so real.
It was so real.
I'm sure it was, babe,
but nightmares can't hurt you.
So, you remember when
Mirror Monarch blasted me
- with her gun?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, ever since that blast,
we've had these crazy headaches.
Last night, everything gets fuzzy,
Caity passes out.
And then we wake up... totally fine.
But there's two of us.
Uh, Eva's mirror gauntlet
contained a reflective mirror chip.
I think it forced Frost's
cryogenes to rapidly replicate
and create a whole new
form so that she could survive.
Crazy, right?
So can you still hear
each other's thoughts?
Nope. Just sweet, sweet silence.
And I got to keep my powers.
Caity got to keep the doctor stuff
and science know-how,
which is fine by me.
You always have felt
like two different people.
Now, you just have
two different... bodies.
But don't worry, I'm gonna
figure out a way to get us
back together as quickly as possible,
because I'm afraid the longer we wait,
the harder it'll be.
I mean shouldn't we be
focusing on that berserker
who killed Abra Kadabra instead?
Frost has a point.
Where are we with Fuerza?
Fuerza.
Spanish, for strength.
Look, She-Hulk was taken, okay?
Well, uh, still no sign of her,
but Barry has figured
out how to track her.
- Oh, good.
- Yeah.
'Cause if Fuerza can
survive an antimatter blast,
that kind of puts her on a
whole other level of baddie.
Like, a "wet your pants" level.
Satellites detected
an isotopic signature?
That's Fuerza. Where's she headed?
Here, right now.
What's with all this
thunder and lightning?
Is Fuerza a speedster too?
Barry.
Who is that?
Help me.
I just got the Speed Force
restarted, now this happens.
And what about your
speed? Has it been affected?
No. At least not yet.
I'm still trying to figure out
how this is even possible.
I have no idea.
I have never seen biometrics like this.
You've never had a god for a patient.
The Speed Force took this
form right after H.R.'s funeral.
It's like Zeus coming down from Olympus,
disguised as a mere mortal.
Okay, but why would a
god be asking for our help?
Whatever the answer is,
I need to figure out a way
to accurately monitor her recovery.
- Holy mother.
- You good?
Yeah, just give me a minute.
She's wearing my
Speed Force gauge now.
Right now, it's red.
If it changes, hopefully that'll tell us
her power levels are recharging.
And if that's the case,
maybe she entered a comatose state
to help heal herself.
Makes sense, and when she recovers,
she can tell us who did this to her.
It.
Maybe it's the same
thing that can rip through
an antimatter bomb
like it's tissue paper.
Those are residual geothermic isotopes.
They're all over her.
You think Fuerza did this?
Oh, that must have
been one hell of a fight.
Not as big as the fight
we're gonna take to Fuerza.
Okay, but this isn't just
some run-of-the-mill meta
we're talking about here.
Whatever Fuerza is,
she's powerful enough to
hurt the frickin' Speed Force.
And what if she doesn't wake up?
What happens to you?
Look, we've faced big threats before.
Crisis, Savitar, Thawne.
We beat them all.
If Fuerza did do this,
she should be afraid of us.
All right, I'll keep
looking for isotopes.
And I'll keep monitoring
the Speed Force.
You think Fuerza's gonna come back
and finish what she started, don't you?
I already watched the
Speed Force die once.
I'm not gonna let that happen again.
Yeah... yeah, just call me
when you know something,
All right, thanks. Bye.
- Sorry.
- That's okay.
Um, Dad,
what do you know about the robbery
at CC Mercantile?
Robber waltzed in and out,
because the night guard
was catching Z's at his desk.
Why the interest in an
open and shut case?
Well, the guard told "The
Citizen" a different story
this morning and I figure I
can help him get his job back
if I can break the real story.
He didn't doze off, Dad.
He had a vision of
his abusive stepfather
stalking him in the bank,
realer than any nightmare he's ever had.
The robbery went down at 11:09,
- last night.
- Mm-hmm.
Around the same time
that Cecile was having a nightmare too.
Damn.
If we've got some kind of
Freddy Krueger meta on our hands,
we'll find him.
I'll get Korber to pull any
calls about weird visions.
Kristen Kramer.
I'm with the Governor's
Municipal Logistics Commission.
I wasn't expecting
you till this afternoon.
It's good to finally meet you.
Yeah, I like to get a head start.
In my experience, if
you're not early, you're late.
You must be the Captain's daughter.
I read about how you
survived the abduction
into that... mirror dimension, was it?
Sounded terrifying.
I've survived worse.
Impressive.
Didn't mean to interrupt.
We can chat tomorrow, Captain.
- Lunch is on the governor.
- Sounds good.
Where'd she say she was from?
State Logistics Commission.
Why?
Just another hunch.
Dope belt buckle.
Ha-ha. Not a belt buckle.
This is the Firestorm Matrix.
Okay...
I helped Thawne build it
to combine Ronnie and Stein
into Firestorm safely.
And... that's gonna help put
me and Caity back together?
You can thank Caitlin,
she figured it out.
All we have to do is
just reset it to her DNA,
and your RNA... we're
basically just resetting
fusion to fission.
This baby just needs
a few hours to charge
and that's it!
We can get you back to your normal,
two minds, one body existence...
that's a Tuesday for you.
Wow, that was fast.
It's not so bad being separate.
For Caity, I mean, you know.
She can finally watch "This Is Us"
without me screaming
"Turn it off!" in her head.
Frost, what have I said
about disparaging "This Is Us"?
- They're so weepy.
- That cast is too precious
for this world. Listen,
based on how relieved
Caitlin was to figure out this fix,
I'm guessing she actually misses
hearing your frosty
tones inside her head.
Okay, I'm done with you.
Now we wait.
I want to keep checking the
satellites, make sure we don't
get hit with another
isotopic signature surprise.
Whoa.
So that's the Speed Force?
Uh, Iris already texted
me about everything.
What's wrong?
I had a nightmare,
but it was more like a vision.
I don't know, I thought, maybe
with my powers expanding
lately, Caitlin could
check out my noggin.
Hey... hey, are you okay?
No, it's happening again,
It... it's like someone's
stabbing my brain.
- I'm gonna get Caitlin.
- No, no, no.
Barry, Barry it's...
It's not medical.
It's my powers.
It's like they're picking up
raw fear.
There's a robbery downtown.
It's okay, really. I'm fine now.
Are you sure?
Yeah. You should go.
Hey,
I'll keep an eye on her.
Go.
It's gonna crush us to death!
Flash, thank God.
You have to stop that
creature, it's gonna kill us!
There's...
Where are you...
Oh, you gotta go so soon?
- Ooh.
- So let me get this straight.
You made those guards
hallucinate some kind of
Godzilla rip-off that
almost squashed them?
Well, I suppose that is an accurate,
if not immensely reductive
assessment of the situation.
So, yes. I scared the hell out of them.
And that was after showing them a vision
of a dozen bystanders
getting eaten alive
by a very hungry kaiju.
It's horrifying when
you think it's your turn.
Okay, um, look. Whoever you are,
I really don't have time for this.
My, my. How rude.
And from a superhero?
Is that actually allowed?
Okay, I apologize for the rudeness.
But I hope you enjoy Iron Heights.
'Cause I really do have
bigger problems today.
Not yet, but you're about to.
Hey, I just got another
geothermic isotope reading.
It's coming from your location.
Scared yet?
You will be.
Jesus. Damn.
You can't stop me, Flash.
And you never will.
No, I'm not afraid of you anymore.
This is just a hallucination.
Which means you can't hurt me!
Time to repent.
You lose, Barry.
Barry?
Barry!
Your vitals were spiking,
but they seem to have stabilized.
Your speed healing kicked in.
What the hell happened out there?
I... I was hallucinating.
Thawne, Savitar...
they were trying to kill me.
It was like...
Like a nightmare come to life?
Yeah.
Like the guards in the truck.
Wait, like you. You had
a nightmare last night.
Yeah.
Someone is broadcasting
fear into their victims,
and I'm tuning into it like an antenna.
Fear I get.
Hallucinations can make you
freak out but not bleed out.
Whoever's doing this must be inciting
extreme psychosomatic reactions.
Barry's mind literally tricked
his body into hurting itself.
So if you die in the hallucination...
Then you die in real life.
Well, he carried traces
of the same isotopes
we linked to Fuerza.
That means we can track him too, right?
Right. And it means that
Fuerza and Psych must
be connected somehow.
Psych?
He's a psychic psychopath,
causing psychosomatic symptoms,
I mean, the guy
practically named himself.
He's only dangerous
'cause he got inside my head.
Cisco, do we still have
the mental dampeners
we used to fight Grodd?
We can try and repurpose them
to repel Psych's hallucinations.
Do it. If we can keep Psych
out of our heads, he can't hurt us.
What?
That must have been terrifying,
being trapped in that nightmare.
I mean, I'm... I'm fine.
Really, I'm fine. I mean,
we beat those Big Bads already.
Psych's no different.
Barry, uh...
You did a background
check on a public official?
I've only ever heard
of one other person
using the phrase
"if you're not early, you're late."
"Citizen" 's go-to military source.
Kramer served.
Yes, she served, but I think
she's also lying about why she's here.
Dad, I found her file
in the D.O.D. database.
Half of it's redacted.
What if she's not here to help?
Iris,
are you sure this isn't a reaction
to what happened with Eva?
I mean, she lied to you for weeks.
Dad, I am not afraid
of being deceived,
I'm afraid of not trusting my gut.
Something is off with Kramer, I know it.
Please, read the file.
Okay, okay.
These rapids are hardcore.
Can Caity swim?
What if... when she and I split,
I got swimming, and
now she needs floaties?
No one's gonna
need floaties, all right?
You two are gonna be
peanut butter and jellied again
by the time we tear up that river.
Frost!
Or not.
The Firestorm Matrix
has been sabotaged,
only someone tried to make
it look like it short-circuited.
Before you go blaming Frosty...
I ran the adapter
through an infrared scanner,
and guess what the temperature was?
162 degrees.
Fine, I broke your
stupid, precious Matrix.
Why?
Why would you do that to us?
It'll be weeks before
we can even consider
another fusion attempt.
Because, maybe I
don't want to recombine!
Why not?
Well...
Call me when you figure it out.
You know,
this actually reminds me of that scene
where Rebecca and Jack are fighting...
Oh, look at that.
Let's go, we gotta go.
Satellites picked up
Psych's isotopic signature
downtown at the Clearly Capital offices.
Time to put these
mental dampeners to work.
And kick some psychic butt.
5.3 trillion gone.
It's all gone.
Oh, God. I'm ruined.
Hey, i-it'll bounce back.
The DOW only dropped 789 points.
It'll bounce back. It has to.
Oh, I could do this all day.
Oh, it's you again.
Well, that's disappointing.
We're not gonna let
you hurt any more people.
Oh, I haven't hurt anyone today.
I have freed them from
a system that brings
fortune to the fortunate
and dooms the rest.
Pretty poetic, don't you think?
What... what is this guy's deal?
I think he's overcompensating.
I don't like your friends, Flash.
Also, if you think your flimsy
dampeners can stop me,
perhaps you all could
use some freedom too.
Killer Frost?
You're under arrest for
your crimes against the city.
What? No.
No, I'm one of the good guys now.
Tell it to Judge Tanaka.
We have a witness.
One who told us everything you've done.
Who turned me in? Was it Mark?
No.
It was Caitlin Snow.
No, no, no.
How could she...
No.
This can't be how it ends.
How could she?
Someone's back for seconds.
You already showed
me my greatest fear.
It won't scare me twice.
Oh, Flash.
Those Big Bads aren't
your greatest fear.
This is.
No. No.
No.
No, please...
No, no, no, no...
No.
Sweet nightmares, people.
First Fuerza, then the
Speed Force shows up,
now this too?
Why can't I stop shaking?
Your biometrics are all elevated.
I mean, your amygdalae are in overdrive.
Wait, we had panic attacks?
Extreme ones, Psych
doesn't just manipulate
your fear, he elevates it.
But your cortisol levels
are slowly stabilizing,
- which means...
- Psych's powers
have a residual effect.
And Barry has had a double dose.
Where's Frost?
She wanted to be alone.
Even the Ice Queen was
freaked out by whatever she saw.
The mental dampeners didn't work.
Psych must have
overpowered their circuitry.
Which means, the
next time you fight him,
we won't be able to protect your mind.
The next time?
How are we supposed to anticipate him?
Stake out the banks?
No, he's not after money.
Remember, he said
he... he wants to free people
from the power it has over them.
So what? He has an axe to grind
- with the system?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It explains why he attacked
the Cleary Capital offices.
He doesn't want cash.
He wants chaos.
Well, he got it.
What exactly did he make you see?
Just...
Kamilla, in danger.
What about you? What did you see?
It doesn't matter.
What if it does?
What if there's, like, a clue or
something in what you saw...
There isn't.
Well, you don't know that.
Look, you're gonna have to
face him again, eventually.
Well, what if I can't, all right?
What if he's too powerful
and I can't stop him?
Barry, no one said...
You didn't have to.
Maybe, Psych's gonna destroy
this whole city and everyone in it.
There's nothing I can do about it.
Trying to reconnect the transmitter
to the output circuit?
Turns out I'm better
at breaking things
than I am at fixing them.
Do you want to tell me
what scared you so much
when Psych whammied you?
Come on, we used to share a brain.
I know you don't scare easy.
I was under arrest,
for all the crimes I
committed as Killer Frost.
And you were the one who turned me in.
I would never do that.
I know.
Look, ever since you
let me take the wheel,
I got to live my life,
not just half the
time, but all the time.
And I really liked it.
And I don't want to go back
to living my life just half the time.
And I was afraid you'd
hate me for saying that.
I would never hate you.
You're my sister.
You can always tell me how you feel.
I don't know how.
I mean...
I may be the strong one, but...
you're the brave one. I mean,
you're fearless!
I mean, ever since I got
in touch with my feelings,
I just...
I'm scared,
all the time.
Sometimes I don't even know why.
You think you're the only one
who gets scared sometimes?
Ever since we separated,
there's been this deafening silence
inside my head, where you used to be.
And it terrifies me.
That's why I've been so desperate
to put us back together.
Why I got so upset when
you broke the Matrix.
It's 'cause my biggest fear in life
is living without you.
Mine too.
Well, why don't we
face that fear together?
You mean...
Maybe two Snows,
really is better than one.
My apartment has an extra bedroom.
I could use a roommate, what do you say?
I say...
"This Is Us."
Cecile, I'm sorry. I
just... um, needed a minute.
Okay.
You do know that you're
not the only one who's been
whammied with more than one
dose of Psych's fear, though?
You've been picking up his
energy every time he shows up.
Last night, I saw...
I saw a nightmare,
where I couldn't control my own powers.
It was terrifying.
It's been really hard to keep
my own fears at bay today.
I spent last year so afraid
of losing everyone I loved
in Crisis, I never thought I'd
have to face that fear again.
Psych showed me...
People I love,
dead.
Fuerza had killed them.
We've taken on the impossible,
so many times.
Something about these
new threats feels different.
Bigger.
And for the first time since Crisis...
I'm sc... I'm scared.
Sometimes, when I'm scared
I ask myself, "What would The Flash do?"
Seriously.
Barry,
you run through fear,
every time you save this city.
Honey, you just gotta
find some of that courage
for yourself.
Guys, we just detected
Psych's isotopic signature.
It's expanding, all
over Sandoval Heights.
Cecile,
you sent your own fear into Top.
Do you think you could
do that on a bigger scale?
D... Me? No, no way.
Barry, I could barely broadcast
one emotion across a room.
Then let's get you some help.
Barry?
Are you insane?
I know, it sounds crazy, but,
DeVoe built this chair to
expand his mental capacity
on a massive scale.
Yeah, yeah,
and it turned him into a supervillain!
But you won't,
'cause you're gonna
use it to save the city.
I can feel all your
fear, Central City,
and it feels exquisite.
Please... please let me out.
Let me out of here, please!
It's too much.
Too much!
I can't take it!
Mom, Dad?
Please don't leave me here.
Why won't you come home?
Get away from me!
- Everything's burning!
- Help me!
The walls are closing in!
- Cecile, you good?
- Nope!
Not even close to good.
I... I am sitting in a death machine.
What if this thing fries my brain?
Wh... what if this chair
turns me evil like the Top?
What about that?
As a medical professional,
I promise you will be okay.
- Okay.
- Probably.
Flash, where you at?
I'm approaching Psych's radius.
Okay.
Do it.
I can't breathe!
Make it stop!
It's working.
I can... I can...
feel people's minds,
thoughts, all over the city.
I can feel Barry.
His amygdala is spiking.
Barry, can you hear me?
Cecile is connected to your mind.
Whatever you're
seeing, fight through it.
This isn't real.
It's not real.
You got us all killed, Barry.
I trusted you.
Why didn't you save me?
When you let me die,
you killed our children too.
Barry can't hear us.
He's caught inside his nightmare.
He's lost.
I'm diverting all satellite
power to the comms.
Listen to me, Barry.
You have to get through this.
Cisco, I don't know if I can.
Yes, you can.
You are strong enough, I know you are.
We can't do this without you.
- You're a coward, Barry Allen!
- You'll lose us again.
All because you're too afraid.
Too afraid to open your eyes.
You're right,
I am afraid.
But I won't let that fear control me.
He broke through!
Cecile, now!
Barry,
I can feel your courage.
You're too late, Flash.
Guys, it worked.
- Cecile did it.
- I did it.
You did it.
- I did it!
- You did it.
Guys,
I think I need an energy bar.
Your frontal cortex is healing,
but the part that controls motor control
is still falling behind.
No trace of Psych or Fuerza.
Well, either way,
at least now we have
proof they're connected.
When I struck Psych with my lightning,
he shook it off easy, but
just for a minute, the lightning...
it stayed with him.
Was it glowing?
Yeah.
Same thing happened
when you fought Fuerza.
I threw everything I had at them,
we all did.
They just kept coming for more.
Luckily, your powers
are getting stronger, too.
Well,
chair did most of the work, but thanks.
I don't know, you kicked some
pretty serious psychic ass out there.
Might have to teach Martian
Manhunter a thing or two.
Barry!
Is it Psych?
No, no. This is something else.
I'm getting the same
readings I got off Nora.
I need to heal myself.
Open the cryo-pod.
No, Barry. That'll put you in a coma.
It's the only way.
Logistics compliance.
Is that what you were doing
when you were working in Gotham?
I've made a few trips there.
I'm a big Knights fan.
And I called my buddy
who'd been working
the Gotham beat for more than a decade,
pretty high stakes game you played.
And...
There is this.
So I don't know what your goal is here,
but, if you're gonna
be in my precinct...
how about we cut the bull,
and you be honest with me.
Fair enough.
I wasn't planning to announce this
until I got my bearings.
On the orders of the governor,
I'm here to locate and apprehend
a rogue meta-human, whatever the cost.
And quite frankly,
it's about time someone
address the long-standing issue
this precinct ignored.
You want to arrest The Flash?
No... he's clean.
So far.
I'm here for someone far more dangerous.
The meta-human fugitive
known as Killer Frost.
How is he?
Better. I think.
Barry's system was overwhelmed
with the same strange signatures
that I found in Nora's system.
His vitals have stabilized a bit,
which is good news, but
as to when he'll be fully healed,
it's difficult to say.
If Psych or Fuerza
were to attack right now,
we're totally on our own.
Because I wasn't fast enough.
Nora.
This physical form is new for me.
I didn't know its limitations.
I can feel how weak he still is.
How weak we both still are.
What happened to Barry?
He was attacked by a
powerful meta-psychic.
Who showed him his greatest fear?
That same psychic was
the second of my attackers.
Fuerza and Psych? They both hurt you?
Who are they?
I think...
they're just like me.
www.TUSUBTITULO.com
-DIFUNDE LA CULTURA-