Previously, on
"Young Sheldon"...
You can't be my lab assistant.
There's a wait list of students
and I just can't give you
special treatment.
Not with that attitude.
Hello?
Can I be your lab assistant?
If I say yes, will you
please stop hounding me?
- Absolutely.
- Fine, you win.
I understand my role here.
In fact, I noticed a flaw
in your reaction rate,
but I kept it to myself
because I know my place.
- What is it?
- Nice try.
Fire!
Was it too much oxygen
in the reagents?
See, you didn't need
my help after all.
My role
as Dr. Linkletter's lab assistant
was progressing nicely.
I had mastered operating
the manual particle collector,
AKA a broom.
I may not always recognize
sarcasm,
but I sure know how to use it.
Sheldon,
I've hit a bit of a roadblock
with the solar
neutrino detector.
Why don't you come have a look?
Are you saying you would like
meto take part in your experiment?
Well, I think a fresh set
of eyes might be helpful.
Because my previous
observationsproved correct?
Yes.
And had you listened to me, the
lab wouldn't have caught fire?
Yes.
So just to be clear,
at the tender age of 11,
I'll be officially participatingin
an academic study.
Will you do it or not?
Absolutely. Here you go.
What am I supposed to do
with this?
Well, if you can't figure thatout,
no wonder you need my help.
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain
♪ I bet I could be your hero
♪ I am a mighty little man
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
Do we have another
hair dryer?
This one broke.
Just use a towel.
So my hair can look like yours?
I don't think so.
Go look in the garage.
Thank you.
I like my hair.
I may have been
part of an academic study,
but I wasn't the only Cooper
on the verge of making
a great discovery.
Sheldon's tests.
I'm gonna be rich.
Missy, ten minutes.
Okay.
Whatcha looking at?
Uh, just Pastor Jeffand Mrs. Sparks.
They were out there
the other day, too.
Oh.
How come you don't go with them?
They didn't invite me.
Ouch.
Rough start to your day.
So, the problemthat I'm running into
is I can't getthe inner sphere
to remain suspendedin the buffer liquid.
Have you tried wrapping
the sphere in copper wire?
I did, but it just slips out.
Perhaps we could suspend it
in some sort of sleeve.
That would prevent
lightfrom getting through.
Hmm.
I wonder if my thinking
would be more effective
if I had a beard to stroke.
It's one of the few aspects of
puberty I'm looking forward to.
Hey, Tam.
Hey. What if I told you
you didn't have to study
for your chemistry test tonight?
Why?
'Cause I found this.
Cool.
But how do you know
we're gonna get the same test?
I checked... we've been taking
the same ones all year.
And teachers call uslazy?
I know.
Well, thank you.
Hold on now.
I ain't just givin' it away.
How much?
Five bucks.
It's worth it.
If I get another B,
my mom will kill me.
Hey, I don't just sell tests.
I bring families together.
♪ Take the Lord,
praise the Lord... ♪
Get this.
I drove past
the Methodist church
and you know
what the sign out front said?
What?
"Friendship, pirate ship,
try the best ship... worship."
Clever.
That was our sign last year!
I wrote that!
Isn't the most important thing
that it might get more people
to go to church?
But whoever did it
has the sin of stealing
on their soul now,
so at least there's that.
There you go.
Oh, um...
I saw
you and Brenda Sparks
out for a walk this mornin'.
That's fun.
Yeah.
Nice way to start the day.
Yeah. Um...
I'd go with George,
but he's a gym teacher,
and as a group,
they're not much for walkin'.
Well, you keep asking,
maybe he'll come around.
Good idea, thank you.
It's not just
witty church signs up here.
I never thought a sphere
suspended in mineral oil
could be so exciting.
Eight minutes and
it hasn't moved.
So far so good.
Oh, boy,
my heart is pounding.
I hope I don't turn
into an adrenaline junkie.
What's going
on in there?
This is a prototype
of a solar neutrino detector.
We need to keep
the sphere suspended
precisely
in the scintillator.
Speaking of scintillating...
No.
Sorry.
Darn it.
Ah, the oil must've
dissolved the adhesive.
Well...
ready to hit the road?
Please, not yet.
We're so close to cracking this.
Just ten more minutes?
Fine.
Oh, boy.
Yes!
I wasn't even at that school,
and I was still boosting
its grade point average.
You got biology?
Depends. You got money?
Yeah. I got biology.
Perhaps we could create some
sort of a cocoon to suspend it.
Out of wire? Or nylon.
But I wouldn't know
how to weave it around a sphere.
I'm not a genius,
but it sounds to me
like what y'all are talking
about is, uh, crochet.
I suppose we are.
Because with crochet, you can
make all kinds of shapes.
Intriguing.
Hell, I even crocheted
a cover for Jolene.
I'm sorry?
That's my bowling ball.
She likes to name inanimate
objects... it's odd.
Or whimsically charming.
Connie, would you help us
detect solar neutrinos?
Really?
You-you-you want me to be
a part of your science thing?
Indeed.
Well...
sure, why not.
Excellent.
And just like that,
my meemaw had been seduced
by the siren call of science.
But before we unravel
the secrets of the universe,
I'm gonna hit the John.
Oh... of course.
And bless the hands
that prepared it.
Amen.
- Amen.
Where is everyone?
Georgie's out and Sheldon's
at the university with Meemaw.
A lot of pressure on me
to keep things fun.
Hey, I was thinking
after dinner, maybe you and I
could go out for a walk.
Why?
Pastor Jeff and Brenda have
been doing it, might be nice.
So go with them.
They didn't invite her.
She was all upset about it.
Well, you get left out
and I get punished?
A walk with your wife
is punishment?
You're up, say somethin' fun.
I think Pastor Jeff
and Mrs. Sparks
might be talking about Billy.
What's going on with Billy?
He's been getting
in trouble at school.
How is that fun?
It's gossip. Gossip's fun.
Poor thing.
Brenda did say he was
having trouble adjusting.
Maybe I should see
if she's doing okay later.
Great idea.
I'm not walking, good job.
So what am I
making this thing out of?
We were using wire,
but that might be
difficult to
crochet with.
Oh, please,
I could crochet barbed wire
with a chopstick if I had to.
I admire your bravado.
In this case,
isn't it the feminine,
"bravada"?
I've never heard
the term "bravada."
Let's just go
with "chutzpah."
What's chutzpah? It's like moxie.
Oh, I do like moxie.
I admire your moxie.
However, I believe
that nylon thread
would be the best choice.
True, it's chemically inert
and would allow
more light to pass through.
Nylon thread.
Done.
Brava. That one
I know is a word.
Can I ask...
why exactly are we looking
for solar neutrinos?
Other experiments have only
seen about half the neutrinos
coming from the Sun.
And we'd like to
figure out why.
And what happens if we do?
They will tell us
what kind of nuclear reactions
are going on there.
In the Sun?
Yes.
That's so far... how?
Neutrinos are made deep
within the core of the Sun.
They have to go
over a hundred times
the radius of Earth
just to get out.
Mm, kind of like
how you can drive
all day and still
be in Texas.
Exactly, then they have
to travel another
93 million miles
just to get here.
Huh. Neutrinos are essentially
direct messengers
from the center of the Sun.
That's why we're
building the prototype.
And I get to be a part of it?
You do.
Damn.
Is there any money in it?
No.
Damn.
Hello?
Hey, Brenda. It's Mary.
Oh. Hey.
Hi. I was just checking in,
seeing how you're doing.
How am I doing about what?
Well, I heard that Billy
might be having
a tough time at school.
Well, you know what, he'll be
fine, so thanks for calling.
Okay.
Um, if there's
anything I can do,
or if you ever want to talk...?
Good to know. Anything else?
Uh, no, that was it.
Okay. Bye.
That night,
my meemaw was so inspired
to be part
of our science experiment,
she began working on it
as soon as she got home.
♪ Fight till the end
♪ 'Cause your life will depend
♪ On the strength
that you have inside... ♪
She was in the zone.
♪ Standin' out in the crowd...
She was focused.
She was determined.
She was also 68
and had eaten a lot of pizza.
And the Nobel Prize
for Science goes to Connie Tucker!
♪ You're the best around...
Oh, my goodness,
y'all are so sweet.
I want to thank
my brilliant grandson Sheldon
and his pal Dr. Linkletter,
for bringing me in
on the experiment.
I'd like to thank my Aunt Linda
for teaching me to crochet
when I was knee-high
to a June bug.
And everyone, for making me...
"The Meemaw of Science."
♪ Oh, you're the best around... ♪
Meemaw! Meemaw! Meemaw!
♪ You're the best around
♪ Nothing's gonna ever
keep you... ♪
Being a good entrepreneur,
my brother realized his supply
of my old tests was limited.
So he did something else he
was good at: Lie to my father.
Dad, you ever use the
copy room at school?
Sometimes. Why?
I need to make some copies for
a school project I'm working on.
Uh, it's not really
for students.
You know, they keep it locked.
So, you have a key?
I'm not giving you my key.
Why not? Well, because I know you,
and therefore don't trust you.
I told you, it's for school.
Great, then bring it
by my office tomorrow
and I'll make copies.
Never mind.
It's not on my key chain!
Dang it.
It was
however, in my dad's drawer at work,
leading my brother
to do something
he had never done before:
Get to school early.
Sucker.
It's like printing money.
You look beautiful.
Shut up and kiss me.
Oh, Cheryl.
Hutchins:
Oh, Hubert.
John Sturgis.
Hey, John.
Connie.
So nice to hear from you.
You'll never guess
what I'm doing.
Tell me.
I am working on a solar
neutrino detector.
Wow. I was gonna guess making
soft-boiled eggs.
Yeah, Sheldon and Linkletter
asked me to help them out.
Oh. Linkletter's involved.
Oh, well, he's not so bad.
You and he aren't...?
Oh, no, no, no.
I'm still seeing Dale.
Okay, good.
I can handle you with a guy
who sells volleyballs,
but you with another scientist,
that'd be like
a dagger in the heart.
No daggers here.
So tell me
about this experiment.
Well, I don't know if you know
this, but solar neutrinos
are like little messengers
from the center of the Sun.
I did know that,
but it's delightful
to hear you say it.
Well, enjoy, 'cause that's about
all I remember.
So, what's new by you? Well, let's see...
Uh, oh, yesterday I had
my first breakfast burrito.
Mm.
Good for you. How was it?
Confusing. I ordinarily have
burritos for lunch or dinner.
I don't know
how to respond to that.
You're working on an experiment
and I'm eating dinner
for breakfast.
It's a crazy world.
I've got to get back
to the library.
Oh, but this is so much
more fun than books.
Will I be
seeing you tonight?
Oh, you'll be seeing all of me.
I think this might be
my finest work.
And she made my dinner
mittens, so that means a lot.
Oh.
I can't thank you enough.
Shall we apply
the empirical method?
Yes, the empirical method.
Let's apply that.
What now?
I feel like I might've
overstepped my bounds
last night, so I just wanted to
bring you these and apologize.
Thank you.
And I did mean it.
If you ever need to talk,
I'm here.
Appreciate it.
Okay.
It's more than Billy.
Herschel moved out.
Oh, Brenda, I'm so sorry.
Do you want to come in?
Of course.
So what's with the box?
The experiment needs
to be in complete darkness to work.
We watch these monitors
for the results.
Okay, all that's left
is to turn on the cameras.
Sheldon, will you
get the lights?
Yes, sir.
Is that to make it
more dramatic?
It's so that we can better
see the flashes on the monitor.
But a little drama never hurts.
All right, here we go.
Commencement of the solar
neutrino detector prototype
in three, two, one.
I don't see anything.
Give it a moment.
Is that it?
That's it.
We did it.
Phase one is a success.
Congratulations.
Wow.
Look at those
beautiful neutrinos.
Those aren't neutrinos.
What are you talking about?
That's what we're looking for.
That's just radioactivity.
Well, then,
when do we find the neutrinos?
We don't.
This is just the prototype.
You kidding me?
The actual device needed
would be the size of a building.
And that's 20 to 30 years away.
Well, I could be dead by then.
You still may have
helped advance science.
Unless another team
beats us to it.
Yeah.
I'm gonna wait in the car.
If it helps, in 30 years,
I should still be alive.
Boy, you'd think
she'd be happy about that.
Remember, the smart cheater
gets some answers wrong.
I heard I might find you here.
Oh, hey, Mr. Givens.
Would you like to explain why
this was on the copy machine?
Anyone could have
left that there.
It's your brother's
and Tam said it was you.
Fine, but I only left it there
because you came in
the copy room and I had to hide.
What? When? What?
This morning before school.
Uh...
What exactly did you see?
I don't want to talk about it.
Well, I don't want you
talking about it.
Well, I don't want
you talking about this.
I don't even know what this is.
I don't even know what I saw.
- All right, then.
- All right.
Captioning sponsored by
CBS, Warner Bros. TELEVISION
and Toyota.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org